Yeah, they you're right. They bring uh a
little bit different flavor all three of
them. Um you know, the Bane is more of a
a big end power player that can kick
down inside a little bit. Um you know,
Bailey has the speed off the edge.
Impressive. Uh he's got some length. Um
and and then Arll um has has played
everywhere. You know, he's played off
the ball, he's played on the line of
scrimmage. Another guy that that has
length. Uh, you know, he's got some snap
in his hips. Uh, so all three of those
guys are impressive.
>> Said he killed it with the individual
guys. Said it was a great interaction.
Did you feel like minister?
>> It was a great interaction. Yeah. No, he
he did great. Uh, all three of those
guys really uh it was really impressive
just uh you know just going through some
of their tape from the season and the
retention they have. Uh they're all
smart football players. Yeah.
How do you envision the process of maybe
taking some of these guys who have
played a little more middle linebacker
and moving them to the edge and and just
that mixture of experience and where
they find that?
>> That's a great question. Um, yeah, you
have to have a vision for it. Um, and
you know, it's uh you take what they do
best. Um, in the case of Arll, you know,
he's played off the ball, which was
really good. Um, and then he's played on
the line of scrimmage, which is really
good, too. Um, but usually, you know,
you'd prefer the or you'd value higher
really the pass rush. So, if he can pass
rush, uh, you let him line up a line of
scrimmage and pass rush.
>> How do you find how you fine season,
you know, whatever
kind of eval?
>> Yeah, that's a great question. In terms
of scheme and everything else, is that
what you mean? Yeah. Um, I've gone
through just in terms of uh scheme
change before, just in terms of an odd
front and an even front. I've done that
in the past in Kansas City. Uh, and it's
it's really just the edge guys. You got
to you got to find a home for them. Um,
you know, some of these off the ball uh
34 backers are, you know, they're either
full-time DNS or there's some DPRs. Um,
and then some of them have some rush
inside. So, um it's really just getting
together with the staff and we did that
the first uh the first couple of weeks
with our college guys too before the
draft and just getting like player
position profiles of what they're
looking for in these position before we
even kicked off the meetings which I
thought was really helpful. We know you
like the cam.
One of your colleagues this week said
that completely transformed now.
>> I think it depends on why they've had
multiple stops, but yeah, sure. Um I
mean, we used to have a flag on on the
tag if they transferred more than once
uh just to kind of stand out. thought it
was a flagging system. But but yeah, no,
it has changed. The landscape has
changed. And I think it really depends
on on the player and you know, sometimes
you can bounce around too much where
you're just not learning the
fundamentals of the game. Um, which has
happened too, I've seen. Um, where
there's more development once you draft
them. uh especially with the you know
offensive lineman and and and and and
corners you know just technique
fundamentals that if you're not in one
place a certain amount of time you
really can't hone those skills in
>> as you're going through and evaluating
receivers a lot of times in college
there's so little press so especially
like when you have your ex guys on the
wall how do you transfer that to the
league and project
>> that's a good question it's hard you
know the technology now with with uh you
can cut all those plays up so if there
are press man clips uh that they're
they're playing against, you want to see
those. Um and sometimes you just have
to, you know, you have to evaluate
sometimes the strength, too. Um if
they're not getting a lot of press
coverage, you know, how are they the top
of routes and bump and run coverage and
and you try to, you know, evaluate their
strength levels that way. But, uh but it
certainly is a challenge sometimes when
there's so much off-man coverage and um
you know, cuz that's a big part of the
NFL. I think that's the biggest
adjustment for these receivers coming
out. um is is facing man coverage uh
especially press man coverage and
getting off the line of scrimmage.
>> Receivers that are at the top of this
potential number one receivers.
>> I think it's a good clump of receivers.
Yeah. Yeah. Up there there are there are
um you know you know Tate's a really
good player and and Lemon and Tyson. I
mean there's a there's a really good
group at the top. Um and I think there's
good value too in the middle rounds at
receiver position. Mike, with that in
mind, when you're looking at buckets of
talent at each position, how willing
would you be to maybe pass on a guy
who's higher ranked on your board
because there is more depth at that spot
down the down the line? Would you be
willing to kind of play that value game
or do you think you really do just need
to stick with the best players, the best
player we take?
>> Depends how much you really like the
player. Um if if you got three or four
guys that are really close then you can
feel you feel comfortable moving back
that you might get one of those guys. Um
but if if you value a guy much higher
than those other two or three guys then
I've always been you take the player.
>> How much do you feel the responsibility
to give better?
>> You know I think I think we're always
trying to um you know protect the
quarterback and and support him with
weapons. Um, and that's certainly
something that we're we're going to, you
know, focus on here this off seasonason.
We added, you know, a few young guys
last year, uh, in the draft, and they
they had the opportunity to play this
year, too, which was great. Um, but
certainly that's our goal every year is
is to add weapons for for Cam.
>> What do you think the strength of those
drafts are?
>> Yeah, you know, I I think like I was
just mentioned, the receiver group is is
a good group. Uh, I think it's a good
edge rush group. Um, I do think there's
some value at the top and middle rounds
with the corner group as well. Um, it's
good linebacker group, too.
>> I'm sorry.
>> Oh, he's been doing it a long time. Um,
you know, I think he um, you know, just
I' I've never had the opportunity to
work with coach Harbaugh, but just uh,
you know, his leadership, the way he
builds a culture, you know, exactly what
type of team you're getting every time.
It's a tough physical team. Mike,
>> I'm sorry.
>> Yeah, I mean, listen, they they've
always had talent down there. Um and and
you know, I think it all starts with the
quarterback and he he had a good season
down there and um you know, I think
they've always been talented up front
too on defense and um you know, they
found ways to to get to the quarterback
and and play good defense, too. So, like
I said, they've always had talent and um
you know, they put it together last
year.
>> Mike, do you have an updated timeline?
>> I I would just say he's trending uh he's
trending well. He's tracking well for
the offseason.
>> Have you picked up the fifth year option
yet? Do you want to get an extension?
>> Yeah, you know, with with Peter, you
know, he's one of our our better players
and and and we like him here long term.
Um and and the the fifth year option is
always a tool, a mechanism he can use,
but uh we're going to work to to try to
get something done here with Peter.
>> Mike, what do you like about this off
specifically the high ball guys
and what
what tools are you using
those guys that fit this team in that
direction?
>> Length and speed. Um and you see that
with with this group. Um there's a lot
of guys that have length and speed.
>> Um you always looking for for you know
obviously guys that can run guys with
length. Um, but then there's a component
of the in the instinctual feel and and
and especially in today's offenses so
many bunch formations and their ability
to process information fast um is more
um more than ever at this point. So, you
know, I'd say length, speed, and the
ability to process instinctually.
>> Mike, how much would you say that free
agency impacts what you do in the draft?
Say you're able to get a slot wide
receiver in free agency. Would that lean
you more towards looking at a boundary
wide receiver in the draft? Same thing
at edge. If you get a power edge in free
agency, are you looking more for a speed
guy or does that really not factor in?
And again, you just look for the best
player you can get.
>> I think you're you always looking for
the best player you can get, but you
certainly, you know, at this point in
the offseason, you have your two boards.
you have your free agent board, you have
your your draft board and you're trying
to figure out areas, you know, where you
can upgrade at certain positions and if
there's value, you know, and and you're
also looking at the quantity of each
position, you know, is it more of a
chance we can get them in the draft or
is it is there a lesser quantity in the
draft and we think we have to fill we go
fill that need in free agency. So, uh,
that's the strategy that we're going
through right now. Like in terms of
positional value, the running back is
always lately something that you value,
but this year you got a guy that has top
five talent. Jeremiah, where are you on
how you look at that position and and
where it holds value as far as where you
guys are?
>> Yeah, you know, anytime you can get a a
running back like that, especially a
three down running back that can that
can play in the pass game as well. Um
and um and be able to take over game.
You've seen guys in the league now that
can do that. you know, that I think
Gibbs is an example in in Detroit um
that that that can run in between the
tackles. He can, you know, he's he's a
game changer and you can line him up
outside, you can you can use him as a
receiver and um you know, I think um
this guy in the draft, Jeremiah does
that as well.
>> Sales the same thing about about you
mentioned Gibbs as well. Is that kind of
somebody you see him being kind of in
that mode of?
>> Well, I think it's the speed and the
ability to play on three downs. what you
see with those players and they're
tough.
>> What are some things you learn about
your head coach over the last month?
>> Yeah, he's he's very uh very detailed.
Uh he's very organized. Um he has a plan
for everything. Um so those those have
been impressive things and it's all
things that we gathered through the head
coach uh search on him and during the
interview process with him. Um but to
see it now over the last, you know, a
month now. Um how detailed he is with
the staff and um and that's what you
want. You want you want detail
organization. Um and he certainly has
that.
>> Take on the staff assembled under Tim
and
>> Yeah, I think Robert's done an
unbelievable job assembling the staff.
um you know, obviously getting um Brian
Dable on offense and and um you know,
Gus Bradley on defense uh as well. Um
he's he's done a great job. They're
they're all really good teachers. Um
what I've noticed so far was very
explosive in the return game this year
obviously. Do you feel like that there
is another level to him as a receiver
that can be unlocked? And if so, how
much can that help alleviate some of the
need there? Uh yes, I I absolutely think
that I think as the season went on and
he and he, you know, was playing more at
receiver, uh you saw that start to come
on. Um and he works. I mean, he is a Tus
Luke worker. Um and he's going to work
to get better and I do think there is
upside. You know, he can play he can
play outside, he can play in the slot,
too. So, um certainly, uh you know, look
forward to the second year and the jump
that he can make at that position. Mike,
last year you guys prioritized a lot of
players who had a leadership background
or previous captains on their teams. Is
there any kind of theme or trait that
you're looking to kind of check off as
you look for guys this year?
>> I I think that just happens when you go
through and you're looking for the right
type of character piece. Um, and we have
um a process that we go through and we
evaluate these guys, not only the talent
on the field, but also the the personal
character and the and the football
character. And that's never going to
change. So I think a lot of times you're
going to see the same type of players we
get in here.
>> Yeah, I mean there's certainly some good
teams in this division here. Um and
obviously you know the defense stands
out in Jacksonville and Houston and and
um you know what they did in India this
year too. So um yeah know the division
has absolutely gotten better. Um, so you
know, you know, and and and that's what
we're here for now. You know, we're
trying to compete and and try to add
more players, but um but the division is
uh it's tough division.
>> Couple more guys.
>> I'm sorry.
>> We're going through all these
evaluations on everybody right now,
everybody in the roster. So, um you
know, I don't I don't want to put a
timet on it. Um but, uh we're evaluating
all these guys and for all different
reasons. Mike, can you uh talk to
>> Hey, Sam.
>> Yeah, you know, I' I've known Matt for a
long time and uh you know, just first of
all, his energy, you know, he's a
passionate guy. Um his offensive mind um
you know, is is impressive. Um and you
know, just the relationships he has with
players over the years too really stood
out. and I've seen that firsthand. Um,
but just really doing research more on
talking to people and and the human
being and the coach. Um, you know, that
that's why he's he's a really good
coach.
>> How often are you surprised?
>> Um, yeah. No, it does happen every year
that, you know, we'll get back a medical
report and sometimes the player doesn't
even know um that he had something
wrong. So, um, it happens. It happens
every year. There's one or two.
>> Last one. Isolating Cam, I know is
important with our bookings and all
that,
>> but how important is that back
quarterback position, maybe getting a
veteran in there that can kind of
further along
like
>> Yeah, that that that that's very
important part of it. Um that that room
um you know, for Cam is is is crucial
and and my experience always getting a
veteran quarterback almost like another
coach. Um you know, obviously they need
a play if they they have to. Um but
yeah, certainly someone with knowledge
and um you know that'll almost be like
another coach for him in the room is
important.
>> Yeah. No, he's done a great job. I just
talked to Will the other day. He's he's
working out the facility uh training. I
was I was running on the treadmill.
There's a group of guys in there the
other day working out when he was in
there. So, um but but he's been great.
You know, he looks healthy and uh he's
ready to go here for the offseason.
Thanks, Mike. Yeah.
>> Thanks, guys. Appreciate it.